September 31, 1884 		
[It's unclear whether this fictional date holds some special meaning or if this is merely a mistake]
E.A. Poe
In Heaven
The Afterlife (Presumably with God)

Dearest Mr. Poe,
I recently came upon a small volume by Lizzie Doten entitled Poems From the Inner Life in which she claims to channel your spirit.   Though it has been twenty years since this book was published, I wonder if you are not still available for consultation on some matters regarding poetry and the after-life?  I have never before found within myself the makings of a medium, however I would be willing to organize a séance and make a go of it.  It would be preferable, to be most perfectly honest with you, if you would instead prefer to correspond with me via the post.  I'm unsure as to whether the post extends into the afterlife or not, but I have heard much of children that write to Santa Clause and assume that if it can reach him at the South Pole, this letter may have some small hope of reaching you beyond the grave.  If I don't receive a letter within one month, I will assume that it has either not reached you, or you have found no way of corresponding from your current position.  In that event, I will take it upon myself to organize a séance and attempt to contact you that way.

Regardless of how it happens, I am very much interested in discussing two subjects in particular.  First, I found your short fiction William Wilson to be of exceptional quality.  I have been wondering much since then about the notion of doppelgangers and have one or two questions on the matter.  You see I made the acquaintance of a young Hebrew this past summer while awaiting a train in New York.  He saw me reading the above mentioned story of yours and, when I was finished, asked if it would be possible to read it.  In exchange I borrowed from him the most recent copy of the local newspaper.  After reading the story, we spent some time discussing the themes raised by your writing, both of us were especially provoked by the idea of the doppelganger.  He mentioned a Hebrew folktale about a golem, which he believed to be a man made of mud.  Though he was of the mind that there was some connection between the two, he did not know much more about the golem, and his train came before we could finish our discussion.  If I am successful in reaching you, Mr. Poe, I would like to know what inspired this fantastic story.

Most Sincerely Yours,
[Here, unfortunately, the name has been obscured through the smudging of ink as well as the age of the paper]

[it is important to note that at the bottom of the letter is written, "Received answer October 13, 1884."  The implication, of course, is that Poe answered the letter.  However, there is no reply included along with this letter, which itself appears to be the original and not a draft.  This leads me to the conclusion that the "answer" received was in fact this original letter returned via the post for a lack of coherent or deliverable address.]
