February 29th, 1944


Dear W. Benjamin,
I am unsure as to whether or not this letter will reach you, seeing as how you are indeed deceased.  However I recently received a briefcase that I believe belonged to you in life, and felt inspired by its contents to write to you.  First, there is the matter of the manuscript, Die Engel: Jüdische Mystik und der Begriff der Geschichte, which I have translated as The Angels: Jewish Mysticism and the Philosophy of History.  I am quite embarrassed to have to admit that I am almost entirely ignorant when it comes to the German language, and thus have had a difficult time translating and understanding your work.  The title alone took me several hours.  Even in the places where you use French, a language I feel slightly more capable with given its similarity with my own native Spanish, I find the going slow.

So to start, I ask your forgiveness for the tardiness of transmission and publication which your work has had to suffer.  If my speed in translating your work does not pick up soon, and I’m afraid that due to the complex nature of your writing, this will not likely be the case, I will send this along to a dear friend of mine, a young Swiss friend of mine who is a native German speaker, who might have more luck than I.  Further I must ask that you forgive my ignorance of your work on the whole, it is neither in my area of expertise to know such things nor in my language.  As stated, I hope to remedy this soon with the translation of your manuscript.

Second, there’s the matter of this curious letter to Edgar Allan Poe that was included in the briefcase.  Of course, as you may guess, my own letter is occasioned in no small part by the possibility for posthumous communication that the letter suggests.  I wonder if you might not be able to tell me a bit more about the circumstances surrounding the letter and its transmission.  Top most on my list of questions is what I should make of the suggestive note at the bottom that there was in fact a response?  Second, I wonder if you know who sent the letter in the first place?  And finally, why send it to Poe?

Of course, as is to be expected of someone of my advancing age, I would love to know any tidbits of information on the afterlife that you might be able to provide me.  Some measure of solace as regards my inevitable death would be most welcome.  Related to my first question, I would also be curious to know how this letter makes it to you in the afterlife, if it indeed does.  I dashed off a poem a few days ago, something I haven’t done since college and as such, won’t include here because of its poor quality, in which I phantasize [sic] that the post office in the afterlife is the domain of angels.  The small bits of your manuscript that I have been successful in translating and understanding have related to angels, and it seems worth asking you whether any of your thoughts on the matter [of angels] have changed since moving into the afterlife?

I hope to hear from you soon, and further hope that our next contact is in fact via the post and not in person.

Sincerely Yours,
Dr. Moises Cordovero
