February 29, 1984	
[it’s unclear whether this is the date written or the date sent]

Edgar Allan Poe	
[his address of this letter seems inspired by the 1884 posthumous letter to Poe]
Heaven 		
The Afterlife 		

Dear Mr. Poe,

My late wife was something of an enthusiast of your work, though I must admit that I myself have only had limited contact with it.  That said, I have always been generally impressed with what little of yours I’ve read; “William Wilson” perhaps being my favorite. I was struck by the resemblance of the doppelganger in the story with the golem of Jewish folklore [it’s unclear whether this idea came to Pappas-Diamand through the 1884 letter or through his own intense interest in Jewish mysticism].  I’m not sure if you are familiar with the story, but I feel compelled to recount it to you nevertheless, so forgive me if this is knowledge you already posses. 

The story begins with the Maharal. The Maharal was a famous Czech rabbi in the 16th century.  It wasn’t a good time for Jews, and there were frequent pogroms.  Fearing Anti-Semitic violence in the Jewish Ghetto of Praggue [sic], where the Maharal lived, he decided to make a golem that could protect the people.  The rabbi went to the banks of the Vltava river to collect clay, which he used to make the golem. When the Maharal was done making the golem, he recited the proper incantation, an incantation taken directly from the old Kabbalists.  As required, he then inscribed the Hebrew word ‘emet’ on the forehead of the golem, bringing it to life.  In Hebrew, ‘emet means ‘Truth.’ Aleph, Mem, Tav.  

Now, once the golem was animated, the rabbi commanded it to protect the Jewish Ghetto.  Golems have no real intelligence, no free will.  Give them a simple task, and they will carry it out over and over again.  In the earliest legends of Judaic golems, their only real disadvantage was their inability to speak; they were forever silent.  However, the Maharal’s golem had other problems.  While it did its job well and protected the Jews of the Ghetto, it also began to grow bigger.  With each increase in size, the golem got equally more violent.  Finally it got out of control and began killing people.  Fear silently patrolled the streets of Praggue [sic] with the golem. People became so scared of the golem that they asked the Maharal to destroy it.  The Maharal promised he would destroy the golem if Prague promised to persecute the Jews no longer.  With that guarantee, the rabbi erased the Aleph from the golem’s forehead, leaving merely Mem and Tav: ‘meit’ which means ‘death,’ and the golem disintegrated to dust.

I’m sure you can see the connection between this story and what is generally, and forgive me if this offends, the morbid tenor of your own writing.  But forgive me, I’ve gotten off topic, something that seems to happen more often now that I’m getting older, and no doubt made worse by my own tendency to over-indulge the drink.  I understand this is a problem you and I share.  Nevertheless, I want to quite delaying and arrive at the point of this letter: the afterlife.  It’s come to my attention that there is a way in which the deceased can communicate from beyond the grave; a way that the living can not only receive but understand and record.  I have found evidence of numerous people communicating with you after your death [it’s unclear if Pappas-Diamand is referring merely to the 1884 letter itself, the Lizzie Doten book mentioned in the letter, or to some research he has conducted on his own], which leads me to believe that you have some special disposition for this kind of posthumous communication.

This leads me to my proposition.  I would like you to help me reach two other departed souls, Walter Benjamin, who died in 1940, and Marshall McLuhan, who died in 1980.  Of course I will contact them with a similar letter myself arranging the details, but I would like for you to plant the seeds of my idea in their minds.  If nothing else, could you just mention to them that I will be writing and that they can expect to receive a correspondence from me?  I would greatly appreciate this effort on your part.  As a kind of dry run, I’d appreciate it if you could try reaching me through the Jürgenson wave.  It is a radio frequency, somewhere between 1450 and 1600 kHZ where it is possible to pick up the voices of the dead.  I’m not quite sure if you need an explanation of radio since you departed this side of the world prior to its invention, but to put it simply, radio is the wireless transmission of audio signals, by modulation of electromagnetic waves with frequencies below those of light .  I will begin listening on the Jürgenson wave on the first week of April, once I’ve had a chance to purchase and install the proper equipment, recording for one hour every Friday between 9pm and 10pm until such time as I should hear a response from you.

Respectfully Yours,

Dr. Jonah Pappas-Diamand
