August 7, 1984	[see note on previous letter]

Walter Benjamin	
With God
[the transition from using “Heaven” to “With God” suggests Pappas-Diamand may have been uncomfortable with potential differences between Jewish and Christian understandings of the afterlife.]
		
The Afterlife		
			

Dear Mr. Benjamin,

I’m writing you with the hopes that Mr. Edgar Allan Poe has had a chance to talk with you.  If so, then you know that I would like to ask you for your cooperation in setting up a dialogue between you and a Mr. Marshall McLuhan, a Canadian scholar of the media.  After looking over some fragments of commentary on your manuscript Die Engel: Jüdische Mystik und der Begriff der Geschichte, I’ve come to the conclusion that Mr. McLuhan and yourself would have much to talk about.  Both of you have an interest in angels, and their roles as messengers or media.  I have actually been doing my best to redact several notebooks on the matter that have come into my possession, and I am finding that the only way to fill some of the holes in my understanding is to prompt you to talk with Mr. McLuhan about these ideas.  In fact, I am almost positive that such a conversation would prove material enough for a revolution in current mediological study.

I am sure that you are wondering how such a project would work.  I am assuming that Mr. Poe did not fully explain it, but if he has, please forgive the repetition as I endeavor to explain.  I will be recording your conversation via the Jürgenson wave, a radio frequency between 1450 and 1600 kHz.  Every Friday from 9pm until Midnight, I will begin recording on magnetic tape cassettes in the hopes that the conversation will take place.  I will repeat this until either I die or you talk to the point of completion.  I am very hopeful that you will consent to such a discussion, though I have a feeling that you may not entirely get along with Mr. McLuhan, who is a very devout Catholic.   Nevertheless, he is a very interesting conversationalist if the interviews I have seen with him are any indication of his demeanor.

If I could, I’d like to provide you with some starting points and preliminary questions for your conversation with Mr. McLuhan.
	
1)	Could you explain your lost manuscript, Die Engel: Jüdische Mystik und der Begriff der Geschichte, for us some?  What is it about and what did you hope to accomplish by writing it?
	
2)	What is the relationship between angels, messengers, and media?
	
3)	Many people have discussed to influence of Judaism on your scholarship , can you talk about how it affected your writing?
	
4)	What was your interest in E.A. Poe?
	
5)	Talk a little more about Messianic time?

I greatly look forward to hearing from you on the Jürgenson wave, and should you not wish to engage Mr. McLuhan in debate, then I implore you to please reply to my letter in kind. 

Most Respectfully Yours,
Dr. Jonah Pappas-Diamand
