August 8, 1984	[see note on previous letter]

Marshall McLuhan	

Heaven	
[the transition back to using “Heaven” further suggests Pappas-Diamand may have associated it solely with the Christian understandings of the afterlife.]	 
The Afterlife		
			
Dear Dr. McLuhan,

I’m writing you with the hopes that Mr. Edgar Allan Poe has had a chance to talk with you.  If so, then you know that I would like to ask you for your cooperation in setting up a dialogue between you and a Mr. Walter Benjamin, a noted German Jewish thinker in the early half of this century.  I’ve recently discovered that he wrote a volume on Jewish mysticism, angels, and the media, and believe that might find some of this interesting given your own musings on angels as media.  It might also be worth mentioning that you both had an interest in Poe, which as you may have guessed, is one reason I have asked him to work on my behalf on this as my agent in the afterlife.

Further more, the reason I’m interested in setting up such a dialogue is precisely because of this mutual interest in angels, the media, and religion.  I am curious to know your different thoughts on the matter, especially given that you both come from quite different faiths.  Though I am not a scholar of media by training, being merely a physics professor, I am an enthusiast of scholarship in that field.  Being a fellow Canadian, I’ve been a follower of your work since I myself was in college.  As a matter of fact, I was at the University of Wisconsin when you taught there, but was never able to take a class from you given my concentration on physics.

I am sure that you are wondering how such a project would work.  I am assuming that Mr. Poe did not fully explain it, but if he has, please forgive me the repetition.  I will be recording your conversation via the Jürgenson wave, a radio frequency between 1450 and 1600 kHz.  You may have heard something about this discovery during the 1960s and 70s.  Regardless, every Friday from 9pm until Midnight, I will begin recording on cassettes tapes in the hopes that the conversation will take place.  I will repeat this until either I die (forgive my morbidity) or you talk to the point of completion.  I sincerely hope that you will consent to such a conversation; I know that it will without doubt be a fruitful one.

If you don’t mind, I would like to provide the two of you with some questions to use as a jumping off point for your dialogue should you agree to one.  I hope that you do not find them inflammatory or insulting
	
1)	In looking over much of your recorded body of work, including books, articles, and interviews, it seems as if you were in fact disturbed by the new technologies about which you wrote, not celebrating them as many people thought at the time; how did you feel about the new communication technologies?
	
2)	It’s clear that you were a man of strong Catholic faith, but you almost never mentioned it in the context of your work, why?  How did your faith affect your scholarship?
	
3)	Similarly, you rarely mention political beliefs in your work, yet some recent biographers have indicated that you were in fact pro-Fascist; how would you characterize your political beliefs?
	
4)	As I’m sure you know, some people have argued that your books were merely thinly veiled attempts at Catholic propaganda, how would you answer such a charge?
	
5)	On more than a few occasions, you mentioned the idea of media as translating man into angels, explain this further if you would?

Again, I hope that you don’t think these questions out of line, and I want to mention one last time just how much I respect and admire you and your work.  I greatly look forward to hearing from you on the Jürgenson wave, and should you not wish to engage Mr. Benjamin in debate, then I implore you to please consider replying in answer to my questions.

Most Respectfully Yours,
Dr. Jonah Pappas-Diamand
