Cordovero: scholar of the history of the Spanish inquisition and its effects on migration to the new world. 1943-Cordovero was in Havana, Cuba, and outlying cities of historical importance (Baracoa, one of the first settlements founded by Diego de Velázquez), studying the use of Cuba as the staging area for Spanish exploration of the Americas. Returned to his home in Miami via boat on January 2, 1944 (Cordovero NB # 1, p2).  

Arranged for his luggage to be brought by porter to his home, where he would meet it later; Cordovero delivers some papers to his office first.  Next day: Cordovero discovered a black briefcase that did not belong to him.  Calls shipping company-no record of case or owner.  Waits a week before examining the case further.  Though locked, the outside of the case holds clues: shipping labels affixed to case.  Starts in Córdoba, Spain-1941, goes down the Guadalquivir River to Sevilla, Spain.  1942-shipped (by unknown persons) to Havana, Cuba. Mysteriously gets mixed up with Cordovero’s luggage (NB #1, p7).

After a disturbing dream involving an angel (seems like mine!), Cordovero finds key to suitcase.  Inside is manuscript entitled Die Engel: Jüdische Mystik und der Begriff der Geschichte by Walter Benjamin (not yet well know-died 1940). (NB #1, p14).  

C spent several days reading through the 347 page manuscript.  He notes that the majority of it is in German, with a few references in French, Hebrew, and Latin. Cordovero largely unfamiliar with German; knows only English and Spanish.  Makes several attempts to translate sections-especially French parts (he remarked, “French is so very close to Spanish as to be legible and frustratingly-near understandable” NB #2, p9).  Uses German to English dictionary, a German to Spanish dictionary, and a French to English dictionary.  

February 29th, 1944 C writes letter to Benjamin-frustrated with translation?  Inspired by letter to Poe found in compartment of case. (NB #2, p10).  

Cordovero continues attempts to translate for several months.  Why suddenly stop? Final page (29) of Notebook #3-looks like being haunted by a dream or series of dreams similar to the initial one that lead to his discovery of the key.

October 27th, 1945, C sends letter to Dr. Heinrich Shoenfeld in New York.

Doesn’t look like Shoenfeld receives package.  What happened?  

1964-Prof. Donald St. Bernard in Chicago  gets first box via post (St. Bernard NB #1, p2).  Not addressed either!

St. Bernard opens it (brave): discovers locked box (NB #1, p6).  

December 28, 1964: has dream-no details (Catholicism?), but sounds similar-gets key. Opens the box (NB #1, p 11).  

SB reads letter to Shoenfeld inside the box. Unsuccessful in locating either Cordovero or Shoenfeld, NB #1, p13. Reads through Cordovero’s notebooks.  

St. Bernard believes that he would be receiving the Benjamin manuscript-something in C’s letter to Shoenfeld.  Notes that he has just seen a recent newspaper article about Gershom Scholem’s October lecture at the Leo Baeck Institute in New York on Benjamin.  B still not well known in English speaking worlds. SB is waiting until he receives the manuscript before commenting on Benjamin (NB #1, p18).

St. Bernard seems very interested in McLuhan-Notebook #2 is devoted to his reading of The Gutenberg Galaxy (1962) and Notebook #3 is dedicated to the just recently published Understanding Media (1964).  Interesting-the final notebook includes SB’s thoughts on Cordovero’s notebooks and themes brought up by the translated fragments of the Benjamin’s manuscript in relation to McLuhan.

The final date in any of the notebooks is August 28, 1965, which matches up with date of death in letter. 

What happened to the boxes prior to arriving at the home of Prof. Pappas-Diamand 20 years later?

Dr. Jonah Pappas-Diamand of Victoria, British Columbia received three boxes over the course of three days, beginning on January 2, 1984 (Pappas-Diamand NB #1, p 2).  Each arrives with the morning post; unaddressed like others.  


Under wrapping JPD finds identical locked wooden boxes.  Tries to pick the locks several times over the course of 4 days after the receipt of the first box! 

Gives up and places boxes in a stack behind the desk in his home office.  

Appears Pappas-Diamand became an alcoholic after the death of his wife several years prior-supported by cause of death listed in letter.

Pappas-Diamand mentions recent interest in conversion to Judaism (religion of his mother), from Greek Orthodoxy (religion of his father). Hopes that renewed spirituality might bring him closer to his late wife, also apparently Jewish (NB #1, p17).

January 6: while drinking heavily in his office and reading a section of the Hebrew bible Pappas-Diamand claims to have been visited by a man shrouded such that he could not see his face initially.  Initially thinks was a burglar, though later speculates that perhaps both the man was of divine origin, and the experience itself a dream or vision (NB #1, p8). Familiar story: Pappas-Diamand wrestled with the man who he assumed had come to steal the boxes.  After long struggle, the man struck Pappas-Diamand in the hip, and though he recalls that the interaction continued for some time after, seems too drunk to rememb what exactly took place (NB #1, p 11).

When JPD woke the next morning, was on the floor of his study with a pain in his hip where he had been struck in the dream.  Nothing stolen, but discovers key in pocket next to injured hip (NB #1, p12).  Too familiar!

Immediately knows what it’s for: unlocks the boxes. Finds one contained the notebooks of Cordovero (Box 2 in the inventory), one contained the notebooks of St. Bernard (Box 3 in the inventory), and the third contained a collection of letters (Box 4, minus Pappas-Diamand related letters, in the inventory).  

JPD spent most of next month and a half reviewing the contents of the boxes as well as conducting research at his university’s library: apparently emeritus following the death of his wife and his decent into alcoholism (NB #1, p15).

Pappas-Diamand notices what he perceives to be references to Jewish mysticism (NB #2, p2).  

Interest transitions into using the writings of Cordovero and St. Bernard to look at the relationship of angels and the media (professor of physics, but interested in mediological phenomena). Especially interested in connection of angels to the works of Benjamin and McLuhan.

JPD starts third notebook outlining his thoughts on posthumous communication-seems inspired by the posthumous letters contained in Box 4 (NB #3, p1). 

Scribbles wife’s name in the margins of NB #3 (p6) with a question mark-thinking about possibility of contacting her. 

Starts drinking again with renewed vigor (may explain why didn’t notice the deterioration of his body due to his terminal illnesses-too drunk to feel pain?): apparently stopped for couple weeks after first getting boxes.  Notebooks becoming increasingly incoherent and essentially fragmented after this point.

NB #3 and #4: account of how Pappas-Diamand came to record the tapes contained in Box #1.  Hard to piece together given quality of writing. Drunk?

Came across Voices From the Tapes: Recordings from the Other World, by Peter Bander (1973) while exploring posthumous letters to Poe and Benjamin.  

JPD learns about Jürgenson wave: Fredrich Jürgenson discovers wavelength.  Called “electronic voice phenomena”- deceased communicate manifestation of “spirit voices occurring on audio recording of weavelength.

Own EVP experiment taking shape in parallel notebooks while already talking about C and SB.  

Pappas-Diamand believes he can arrange a posthumous conversation between Marshall McLuhan (died in 1980) and Walter Benjamin that could be recorded on the Jürgenson wave.  Wow?  Imagine the possibilities.

Wants to continue working through some of the ideas raised in Cordovero and St. Bernard about angels, Benjamin, and later McLuhan.  

Decides to write preliminary letter to Poe (must be inspired by the 1884 letter to Poe (L #1):  believes was answered).  

Poe apparently responded in the affirmative in late July of 1984! Jürgenson wave recording of this is lost.  Writes other letters.

October of 1984, Pappas-Diamand began recording 3 hours of tape every Friday night beginning at 9pm.  

February of 1985 he’s successful in recording the first of two posthumous conversations between Benjamin and McLuhan (NB #4, p 26). Conversation took place almost entirely in French, with German appearing for 15 minutes during the first recording and 27 minutes during the second.  Pappas-Diamand had no familiarity with French, and only a limited knowledge of German (NB #4, p27)-took some German in college, but let lapse.

Transcription of the two 3 hour conversations lasted from February until July: probably because language and poor quality of EVP recordings--also his alcoholism? Seems to have increased in intensity-perhaps connected to the pain from the stomach cancer eating away at his body.

July 17, 1985 (NB #4, p30): starts translating what he has-chose sections of the conversation that took place primarily in German, probably hoping that long-lost familiarity with the language would return.  

Only 4-pages of the translated transcript included in Box 1.  Strange. Fragments seem to be the most directly related to the 11 pages of commentary JPD wrote between September 11 (day after he finished translation) and death in sleep on September 28.  

Maid found him the next day!  According to letter-she cleaned up stuff in office.

Consistent history of materials-takes 20 years to resurface, but never with person intended to receive it-never gets to person in letters.  What happened in the years between?


