9??)ÊTFö…+ñX7õ ÚÂâ p”jµ†?û¸?•Á~’ >Á¸_,i[”á?äÈår? Ë›Œzøß?üç;R™Çoè >5ï™1÷™`t$†?BUjRnO¨’!Nâ^®Së¢ß] /§›´ø?Ô‘ó˜ìÌ+??ï«xthe package from him, I promised to mail it n the morning.  I bid the story farewell and made my way home, feeling thoroughly protected in the folds of the new coat he’d provided me.
In the morning, however, as I prepared to visit the post office, I noticed that there was no address written anywhere on the surface of paper encasing the package.  With no other choice but to return to the store, I donned the wool coat and headed out.  Keeping my eyes peeled for the lantern and sign, I walked by the house twice without recognizing it: the store was gone!  No sign sat out in front, and the door at the bottom of the stairs was blocked by a large pile of leaves and refuse that looked as if it had been collecting there for several years.  In the light of day, I saw that the dark house was in fact burnt out, the glassless windows staring at me sadly.

Back at home I placed the box in the back of the storage closet of my apartment, vowing to take care of it once finals week had ended.  Instead I forgot about the box.  It wasn’t until today, nearly a year after the storm, that the package found its way back into the forefront of my mind.  Upon coming home from my first week of classes, I found the box waiting for me at the top of the stairs.  Thinking my roommate must have removed it from the closet, I went to put it back, only to discover that it was not the same box, but in fact a second, identical box, this one equally unaddressed.  Feeling uncomfortable, I placed it with the first at the back of the closet.  

September 1, 2004
I received another package today, again without any address or postage mark.  I wonder what’s in it?  I’m going to call the post office tomorrow and ask them what’s going on.

October 1 2004
Another box arrived today.  I forgot to call the post office last month.  I’ll definitely do it this time; I’m beginning to find the whole thing disturbing.  No postage mark, no address. Again.

November 1, 2004
The fifth package came today.  It’s like clockwork.  The post office was completely unhelpful when I call last month.  They said they didn’t have any record of the packages.  I tried waiting home to see if I could catch the mailman delivering the package, but somehow I missed it.  I’ll try again next month.

December 1, 2004
No package arrived.   Waited for the mailman again, but I think he came while I was went upstairs because I thought I heard the phone ring.  

December 10, 2004
Final’s week looms, and there has still been no package. I think that’s why I did it.  I felt compelled to retrieve the five boxes from the back of the closet.  I retreated to my room with the boxes.  Fearing that they might contain Anthrax or some kind of explosive, I dug out the old white painters mask and goggles that I used with my power sander.  Using duct tape I attached a swiss-army knife to the end of a broomstick.  With a pair of gardening gloves on, and using the open door to my room as a shield, I clumsily manipulated the broomstick extension of my arm to cut the packaging from the first box.  After a few moments, when no explosion rocked the room, I peeked back around the door to inspect the package.  Seeing no powder that could be Anthrax, I moved closer and found that underneath the paper was a sturdy, if worn, wooden lock box.  Unwrapping the remaining packages I discovered that all five boxes were identical, and all five locked.  Maybe I’ll walk to the hardware store and buy a lock picking set tomorrow since it’s the weekend.

December 11, 2004.
Something strange happened to me last night.  I spent many hours pouring through class notes in a vain attempt to light upon some topic for my seminar paper.  The heat in my apartment mysteriously turned off, so I was forced to retrieve my wool coat from the closet to keep warm.  The boxes, which lay along the wall in my room, had continually drawn my attention away from my schoolwork all night.  The boxes must have so occupied my mind as to have become part of the residue of which my dreams 
\  V:k?›§;¬©i›R;;\ë å u? Â›V†? ??º\???\?C9æ ¬u•(Jï I“ ¿Î?]ç?‹‡BSòs_	QP5ù?Fzº?Î?ãG?%´t {3qW ?D˜0v  zº¸
\} \¯ $ Ä‘u  °?m?¿Õ +ò ÖñÕŸ¨Cñ;Xÿ9:YÑ^ g±B?,?\?ACioci]gÆ©? ??(ÒL;Úz±?Ô9?Anåé–IÛ
®‹Í??4ìI˜–›†ùx#?{zùwAº®j}ÉŒÖ–?§äæQè•Ûö=òÚ8–mËÒ•
?(ƒo{1±c?—d5æU È? g“? t?ê¸?la»±i"?–\.5Ê±îöÀ?‚ ^?8tph0ËkÄ!â~D
Å T“hd°ëîª6Çÿ¬Ï±ñ: >f§?&üm?Á ä‰Ìx›A4éÖ?É L?&?ñ?‰%??¸k±• ™i ƒî¶¨??CqùÃ’? m•&/æBy#§’ë%i?†'ÀW©Ø:’Xl©Err?'Ò=_ó‹ó)åi7“¨õ©‰Í,?F|ŸNö ŸÆÕØ6?rmù^ô‹ÆÕ¬öU•HW¸†´??5;ø??Õ? h
endstream
[ /ICCBased 10 0 R ]
endobj
12 0 obj
<< /Length 11 0 R /Filter /FlateDecode >>
stream
x?•V]è‚F |ÁWÙ„ù‰Â?Å  /ßDŸóD'!ù"Âe0 ûe<„ù cÒÔS›6˜ D—9b å=f ’U’?FüÈçÚ5-f¥\=”jæ††È
9??)ÊTFö…+ñX7õ ÚÂâ p”jµ†?û¸?•Á~’ >Á¸_,i[”á?äÈår? Ë›Œzøß?üç;R™Çoè >5ï™1÷™`t$†?BUjRnO¨’!Nâ^®Së¢ß] /§›´ø?Ô‘ó˜ìÌ+??ï«xèÓ•-ûÁ?¬õºã ûU2?—!¯?ÊÌ *awek¬ ’&F?ó´µr MJcß+„?”G´bƒ3E<A‚3£ >œÚ[Ä;Uûò¬?$x_Éî?5È
‡‘?+°ù
?È Tç”±—eR• ØL¶¬"„HµAÒÔƒ?ü?Å[Õ7?‡4ÿPBÖ?ß»z©2ˆkL£©‚??âÔïâT  ?1©¬?JÖ–÷MïÒ?ù.O?…Cç ?^?n¡ï÷G @çÏ&†*!DHÈLl
.ü?)?Ù==?sÚo{.aú|ñ?…?ÔyQ|Ú5?7¸ M»†ß•k?EƒY0°†q ©+_ë§Œù?6?{®È‚€ µ=ê ?Gû/ø??Ñ±’ ‚“  Á(ÇVÁ?JÿÔ ?SßµC ;ä®Ÿô]y÷•Ä ºLX,€`<ƒ Àf óåCVlÚ[dV’ ~rÁ?	¬\†3Ç¡?ë:¬Ní —  ÿ‹  ?_”âˆ ô‡] ?ÓÉÓ»i P÷‰Gõ0_ õ;Í‡zŸ?èÖ®:
& ;°d‘¯Ù¥”÷ ?_ o?Çö¸ÁŒ"®ÂÛÍë†?–Ìâ ëIÌx  G 5*úÿ5 —äë sÈ  Ç%?íñ„µœ`=æv´ŸÚ 5 1J ¿; , ù d4p’? P©?ÊÎö1ä‡%f+µ« Á EV¬ã ï>: ÈOC 
V … ?*Ù¥`ÕC?¸4ÊVÎÕ#:Â'Á •õ?jˆ P\Ì?Ï÷
?QÅ‚‡•*…X
Œv?Fz vN+\Hx‚ƒ ™LÆ2±01Kú2'÷0ü 
Èv92uÂl?€€.¯Ä&/ÿŸ?d	A¢\ ~ûâ_{å
SÇuUEç
€È JQ GQ%Œp?äI—93mz§ªÌ»–`è  x˜›
ei?£Ø(Ùgù??PåÛËGU ù9àÂm#Cå°aÇ¢XtPÏŸH (Å  ®)Míe´ë ?›í/ó¯WFÌÅŒ 0œq„lŸ úø 	¸‘;—?ÒìC ¬39î ¶û?ƒìqí
fallen asleep fully dressed atop the covers, surrounded by books.  The light of my room was still on, its yellow hue slowly being joined by the orange of sunrise.  As I came more fully awake, I felt a strong pain in my right thigh, directly where the angel had hit me.  For a moment I was afraid that my dream had followed me into reality, but I quickly realized that it must have been the other way around, for the pain was caused by something, a pencil I guessed, that I must have rolled onto in my sleep.  When I rolled back over to investigate, I found no object beneath me.  It was a moment more before I realized that the object in question lay in the pocket of my wool coat.  Reaching in I pulled out an old iron skeleton key, the five boxes along the wall looking at me with frightening certainty.  Kneeling down before the first box, I inserted the key and, feeling divinely assured that there would be no bodily damage, turned it, bringing forth the click I knew it would.
Once all the boxes were open, their contents exposed to light, I took stock of what I’d been sent; the second, third, and fifth box contained various notebooks, the first a series of cassette tapes along with jumble of loose of pages, and the fourth contained a collection of letters.  The first box appeared to me the most recent, not merely because of the cassette tapes, which at first glance looked to be from the 80s, but from a comparison of the paper in the different boxes.  I estimated that after the first box, they descended in order of age with the second being the oldest of the lot.  Wary of the potential age of some of the items, I donned a pair of glove liners so as to minimize the contact between skin and what could be delicate paper.  Over the next several hours I was able to compile a preliminary inventory of the contents of the boxes.  It’s fascinating.

December 13, 2004.
I’ve been sorting through this stuff for several days now, and a more complete story is beginning to emerge. I’ve made some notes in my second notebook and hopefully I can cross reference that with the letters and maybe even the recordings.  I’m going to listen to those next.

December 14, 2004
I listened to the tapes: six hours, straight through.  It was difficult to make out the words amidst the static, as well as differentiate McLuhan from Benjamin.  The voices were distorted, an apparently common problem in EVP recordings according to the website of the American Association of Electronic Voice Phenomena (http://www.aaevp.com/faq.htm), and the telltale syllable length variability was present in the few French words I could distinguish and understand.  It became a little clearer how Pappas-Diamand could have spent as long as he did transcribing the conversation.  I easily found the place in the recording corresponding to the fragment of translated transcript using the time codes in Pappas-Diamand’s notes.  The distortion in the voices make it all but impossible to hear inflections and tones, so there is little way of knowing anything other than the literally transcribed words.

December 15, 2004
I’ve made a third notebook with the transcript, reproduced from the pages of Pappas-Diamand, followed first by some of his notes attempting to synthesize Cordovero and St. Bernard as well as on the conversation between McLuhan and Benjamin.  This is followed by some of my own commentary.  I apologize for the fragmentary nature of this work, including my own commentary, but I find a certain consistency in working this way given the legacy of scholarship I am working within.
I am referring most directly to Benjamin’s Über der Begriff der Geschichte as well as Passagen-werk, and to the notes that I received in the five boxes from Cordovero, St. Bernard, and Pappas-Diamand.  I would like to point out an additional “lineage” within which I see myself working: Judaism.  I am here referring to the Midrashic tradition of Torah commentary.  I know I try not to quote in my journal—it’s important to keep work and personal life separate, but this whole thing with the boxes has thrown that off some—but this one seems so appropriate. Benjamin, in his essay on Kafka, writes: 
Kafka’s parables, however, unfold in the first sense, the way a bud turns into a blossom.  That is why their effect resembles poetry.  This does not mean that his prose pieces belong entirely in the tradition of Western prose forms; they have, rather, a similar relationship to doctrine as the Haggadah [homiletic Midrash (commentary)] does to the Halakah [ethico-juridical Midrash (commentary)].  They are not parables, and yet they do not want to be taken at their face value; they lend themselves to quotation and can be told for purposes of clarification. (Illuminations 112)
Maybe I’m being a little melodramatic, or even solipsistic, but in using this quote, I mean to suggest that my writing shouldn’t be taken as doctrine, nor merely as parable, but as a kind of Midrashic in-between, as Benjamin asks us to do for Kafka.  Putting myself in the company of Kafka—definitely presumptuous.  If I got a hold of Benjamin’s text then I
à>}  RAö…» ?Fï6u??é] ÷6¥¯öt ˜È¬dÁ $
endstream
endobj
19 0 obj
1283
endobj
21 0 obj
<< /Type /Page /Parent 5 0 R /Resources 22 0 R /Contents 20 0 R /MediaBox
     